tacx.com 2019-06-03

# Privacy policy | Tacx

Tacx is an innovative company with great passion for sport and technique. This passion drives the organization and can be seen in all departments; from purchasing to production and product development to logistics.

Our products and services provide instant access to health and fitness data so you can track your progress and reach personal goals. As we provide you with our products and services, we are also dedicated to safeguarding your personal data, respecting your rights and letting you decide how we use your personal data.

Your privacy is, in short, critically important to us. We, therefore, at Tacx have a few fundamental principles:

  * we don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.
  * we don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products and services and provide you with our products and services, or protect our rights.
  * we treat your personal information with the highest regard to privacy and security.

Tacx designs products and services that can track your everyday health and fitness to help you train and reach your goals. This privacy policy applies to our products that can monitor your fitness and bodily functions (“Products”), our websites, and related services (the “Site”), currently accessible at [www.tacx.com](http://www.tacx.com/) , our software, including the Cloud ([cloud.tacx.com](http://cloud.tacx.com/)), (“Software”) and our mobile applications (each an “App” and together the “Apps”). The Products, Site, Software and Apps are jointly referred to in this privacy policy as the “Tacx Service”. The following statement (the “Privacy Policy”) discloses the guidelines Tacx has established for protecting the information you provide to Tacx during your visit to or use of the Tacx Service. The Site is owned, operated, and maintained by Tacx, e-mail: privacy@tacx.com.

**  
What information about me does Tacx collect and how is it used?**

Tacx B.V. (“Tacx”) is the data controller of your personal data in the sense of the EU General Data Protection Regulation. The principles set out in this Privacy Policy apply to all instances in which Tacx receives your personal data as a data controller for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Through the Tacx Service, you can share your activities. Data collected through an activity may contain the following data about you, your:

  * biography;
  * date of birth;
  * email;
  * first name;
  * last name;
  * heart rate threshold, heart rate zones, maximum heart zones, maximum heart rate, resting heart rate;
  * height;
  * weight;
  * location;
  * gender;
  * profile image;
  * url;
  * user’s universally unique identifier (also known as UUID);

BikeProfile  
A bike profile can be selected by the user. It is linked to the user via a parent field, and may contain the following data:

  * first name;
  * last name;
  * weight;

Tacx uses your data to provide you with the Tacx Service and to help you to make the most of your ride. We for example use your height, weight, gender, age and heart rate to estimate how many calories you have burned and to monitor your progress.

Visiting the Site and setting up a Tacx account  
To use the core functionality of the Site and to access any data collected by a Tacx Service, you must first complete the registration form at the Site and agree to our Terms and Conditions to set up a Tacx account. During registration you will be required to provide: personal information such as your name and email address. You can also use your Facebook or Google account to set up a Tacx account. You can then also choose to share some information from these accounts with the Tacx account. You can always choose to remove Tacx from this account to stop sharing this information. Tacx does not knowingly collect information from children under 13 years old. If we or a third party service provider requires a birth date to order a specific product or service, you will not be able to enter a birth date that indicates that you are less than 13 years old. If you opt-in for the Tacx newsletter during registration, Tacx will use your email address to send you newsletters with updates and news about Tacx. You may remove your name from our email list by updating your profile in the Account section or by emailing [support@tacx.com](mailto:support@tacx.com). We will respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe, and in any event in less than 30 days.

We also collect data if you make a purchase or on our Site on any other Tacx Service. This includes your (shipping) address. If you make a purchase on the Site or on any other Tacx Service, we may also ask you for your credit card and billing information. This personal data is solely processed and handled by our payment providers. Tacx uses a credit card processing company, Adyen, to process your credit card information as required for your order and to ensure that your transaction is secure. This processing company does not retain, share, store or use your personally identifiable information for any other purposes. Tacx does not have any access to the personal data collected by this credit card processing company.

_Activating a Tacx Product  
_When you activate a Tacx Product, you will be asked to download the Tacx App or install Software. You will also be asked to provide information about yourself. This includes information such as your name, age, gender, height and weight. We use this information to calculate your personalized stats – including distance traveled, speed, heart rate and calories burned. Depending on your use of the Tacx Service, this information may be shared with Tacx. We have set out what exact information each component of the Tacx Service collects in an extensive overview to the Privacy Policy.

_Adding data to your Tacx Account  
_You can choose to share information in your Tacx account. This may include information about you such as your equipment and activities, your biking routes, your name, your zip code and e-mail address. If you choose to share any personal information with Tacx, Tacx may store it and use it for internal research and other Tacx marketing purposes, including e-mailing you with special promotions and other programs of interest. If the information is sent as part of a Tacx Service evaluation, Tacx may also use the information to contact you about your comments.

_Syncing your Product_ _ _  
__ If you choose to sync your Product to the Software or App, data about your activities is transferred from your Product to Tacx. Tacx uses this data to provide you with the Tacx Service and also stores this data. We also store data about each transmission that takes place when you sync your Product.

_When using location features_ _ _  
__ Location features such as mapping can be available if you choose to activate this feature. When this feature is active, Tacx collects data such as Gps signals, device sensors, Wi-Fi access points, and cell tower IDs to determine your specific location. This information is stored together with your other account information. When using a mapping feature, your location information will be shared with our mapping service provider to display your location on a map. This information is solely shared for this purpose and will not be used otherwise. You can always choose to deactivate the location feature. Tacx will stop collecting this information when you deactivate this feature.

_Contacting customer service_ _ _  
__ When you contact our customer service for help, we collect your name and email address and any information you may provide us with. We collect and store this personal data to provide you with customer service and to improve the Tacx Service. You may decide to send Tacx personally identifying information in an e-mail message which might contain information or inquiries about the Tacx Service. Tacx will use this information to identify you as a Tacx member and to respond to the electronic mail. Tacx will only use the information obtained to resolve the issue identified in the e-mail. Tacx never sells e-mail addresses. You may change or request deletion of your personal information by contacting [support@tacx.com](mailto:support@tacx.com). We will respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe, and in any event in less than 30 days.

_Contacting other riders_ _ _  
__ Tacx allows you to contact other riders who also have a Tacx account. This also includes the possibility to share data with other Tacx users. This can for example be done while racing or posting comments to the Tacx forum. The data that is displayed is based on the settings in your account. When posting a message in the Tacx forum, your username and profile photo that is part of your Tacx account will be visible to others. You are responsible for all information that is shared with other riders.

_Data that you request Tacx to share_ _ _  
__ You can request Tacx to share your information with other parties. You may for example ask Tacx to link your Tacx account to a third party app, such as Facebook, Strava or Google. Information collected by third parties, which may include such aspects as location data or contact details, is governed by their privacy practices. You should exercise caution, and review the privacy statements applicable to the third-party websites and services you use.

Tacx only collects personal information about you if you voluntarily choose to share it with Tacx. Tacx does not share, rent or sell information concerning Tacx’s members or other users of its Tacx Service to third parties in ways other than disclosed in this Privacy Policy. We have added an extensive list of some third parties to this Privacy Policy.

**Data storage and retention**

Your personal data is stored by Tacx on its servers, and on the servers of the database management services Tacx engages, located also in the United States. Tacx retains data for the duration of the user’s relationship with Tacx and otherwise as required under applicable law. Personal data will be kept for no longer than is necessary for the purposes for which your personal data are processed. We will retain your personal data as long as you are a Tacx user or require our services so that we can provide these services to you.

At the moment you cancel your Tacx membership or withdraw your consent for the processing of your personal information, all your personal data received and stored are erased if no longer needed by us. Unless we are required to retain this personal data by law or to comply with our regulatory obligations. In such a case, we will only keep this personal data for as long as necessary. For more information on where and how long your personal data is stored, and for more information on your rights of erasure and portability, please contact us at [support@tacx.com](mailto:support@tacx.com). We will respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe, and in any event in less than 30 days.

**Cookies**

When you visit the Site, a cookie will be stored on your computer. What are cookies? “Cookies” are small pieces of information that are stored by your web browser’s software on your computer’s hard drive or temporarily in your computer’s memory. The use of cookies is an industry standard and can enhance the user experience and your access to information on a website or other online system operated by Tacx. Cookies are used on most major websites. Cookies may enable Tacx to recognize you and personalize your viewing experience on a website or other online system operated by Tacx.

When you visit our Site or Software, we may collect information about the type of device you use, your device’s unique identifier, the IP address of your device, your operating system, the type of internet browser that you use, usage information, diagnostic information, and location information from or about the computers, phones, or other devices on which you install or access our Products or Services. Where available, our Services may use GPS, your IP address, and other technologies to determine a device’s approximate location to allow us to improve our products and Services.

Generally, cookies work by assigning to your computer a unique number that has no meaning outside of Tacx. Tacx’s cookies do not contain any personally identifying information; Tacx uses them to provide features such as personalization, to save your member ID and to keep track of your shopping cart. Tacx may also use cookies to assist it in delivering content specific to your interests. Additionally, after you’ve entered your member ID and password during a session on Tacx’s Site, Tacx saves that information so you don’t have to re-enter it repeatedly during that session. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually change your browser to prevent that. Not accepting cookies may make certain features of the Site unavailable to you. Tacx may use your IP address to identify you, to administer the Site and to assist in diagnosing problems with Tacx’s server.

Tacx also uses cookies to analyze the use of the Site and to match the content of the Site and ads to your preferences. These cookies are placed by Google Analytics and Google AdWords.

  * We use Google Analytics to collect information about Site usage for statistical analysis: Google Analytics uses a collection of cookies to collect Site information and report Site usage in a partly anonymous form.
  * We use Google AdWords Remarketing for targeted marketing to users that visit our Site. Google Remarketing cookies allow Tacx advertising to be served once a user leaves our Site and visits any Google Display Network Partner enabled Site. When you visit an eligible site, cookies are referenced by that site to display our advertising based upon the history of sites visited by your browser. We also use these cookies to assess the effectiveness of our advertising through this medium.

The information that is recorded in Google Analytics and Google AdWords cookies does not contain any information that can identify you personally. Google stores the information collected by the cookies on their servers. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this Site. Tacx does not have access to or control over these third parties or the cookies, web beacons or other technology that these third parties may use. We are not responsible for the security, privacy of the information collected by these third parties or the privacy practices of these third parties or the content on any third party website. You are encouraged to review the privacy policies of these third parties.

You can remove or reject cookies using your browser or device settings, but in some cases doing so may affect your ability to use our products and Services.

If you wish to opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics on this Site with the effect for the future, please copy and paste the following address in your browser:

<https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

Like most standard website servers the Site uses log files. This includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. In addition, Tacx uses Google Analytics as a method of tracking site statistics and user behavior on the Site. We have attached an overview of our cookies to this Privacy Policy.

We will not associate identifiers from cookies or similar technologies with sensitive identifiers, such as the race, religion, sexual orientation or health of our users.

To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web beacons, please consult the privacy features in your browser. In addition, to find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set on your device and how to manage and delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

**Do Not Track**

Some browsers include the ability to transmit “Do Not Track” signals. We do not process or respond to “Do Not Track” signals. Instead, we adhere to the standards described in our Privacy Policy.

Tacx will only share your personal information with third parties if:

  * Tacx has your consent;
  * Tacx deems this necessary to provide you with the Tacx Service. All companies are contractually engaged in providing us with services like the purchase of products and services, email management and payment processing.
  * Tacx determines that it is required to do so by law; such as in response to a court order or subpoena;
  * Tacx finds that you are in breach of its terms and conditions or any of its policies or usage guidelines for specific Tacx Services;
  * it is necessary in Tacx’s opinion to do so to prevent, investigate, detect or prosecute criminal offenses or attacks on the technical integrity of the Site or Tacx’s network;
  * it is necessary in Tacx’s opinion to do so to protect the rights, property, or safety of Tacx or its employees, the users of the Tacx Service, or the public; or
  * information about you and your use of the Tacx Service may be aggregated with other information collected via the Tacx Service or otherwise used in ways that do not personally identify you or constitute personally identifiable information. This type of aggregated or statistical information may be used by us to improve the quality of the Tacx Service or for other purposes that we may deem appropriate.

Our processing of your personal information will be legitimized as follows:

  1. Whenever we require your consent for the processing of your personal information such processing will be justified pursuant to Article 6(1) lit. (a) of the General Data Protection Regulation (EU) 2016/679 (“GDPR”). This article in the GDPR describes when processing can be done lawfully.
  2. If the processing of your personal data is necessary for the performance of a contract between you and Tacx or for taking any pre-contractual steps upon your request, such processing will be based on GDPR Article 6(1) lit. (b). If this data is not processed, Tacx will not be able to execute the contract with you.
  3. Where the processing is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation, we will process your information on basis of GDPR Article 6(1) lit. (c), for example complying in the fields of employment law.
  4. And where the processing is necessary for the purposes of Tacx’s legitimate interests, such processing will be made in accordance with GDPR Article 6(1) lit. (f), for example to detect fraud.

**Transferring personal data from the EU to the US**

Information we collect from you may be processed in the United States through our Software (Google Cloud Platform). The United States has not sought nor received a finding of “adequacy” from the European Union under Article 45 of the GGDPR. A finding of “adequacy” in short means that the European Commission has decided that this country outside the European Economic Area (“Area”) ensures an adequate level of data protection. We refer, to <https://cloud.google.com/security/compliance/eu-data-protection/> for more information on the safeguards that Google has in place for the transfer the Google Cloud Platform.

**  
What can I do to help make sure the security works correctly?**

Tacx uses bcrypt algorithms to “hash” passwords of users, Tacx does not store its user’s passwords. “Hashing” is the transformation of a string of characters into a value or key, it is a form of encryption. Tacx also uses SSL. The data traffic to the Software (Cloud) is protected by SSL, this also protects the data traffic between the Apps and the Cloud. SSL is a technique used to encrypt the connection between data traffic between for example a website and a server.

To help ensure that these measures are effective in preventing unauthorized access to your private information, you should be aware of the security features available to you through your browser. You should use a security-enabled browser to submit your credit card information and other personal information at the Site or any other Tacx Service. Please note: If you do not use a SSL-capable browser, you are at risk for having data intercepted. Tacx will not be responsible for any compromise of data that is intercepted due to your use of an unsecured browser.

Most browsers have the ability to notify you if you change between secure and insecure communications, receive invalid site identification information for the site you are communicating with, or send information over an unsecured connection. Tacx recommends that you enable these browser functions to help ensure that your communications are secure. You can also monitor the URL of the site you are visiting (secure URLs begin with https:// rather than the normal http://), along with the security symbol of your browser (an open or closed padlock in Netscape or a broken or complete key in Internet Explorer) to help identify when you are communicating with a secure server. You can also view the details of the security certificate of the site to which you are connected. Tacx encourages you to use this to check the validity of any site you connect to using secure communications.

Tacx uses reasonable physical, technical and administrative measures to safeguard personal information you provide through the Tacx Service or in connection with Tacx’s Products and Services.  Please be aware that no data transmission over the internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, Tacx cannot guarantee or warrant the security of any information you transmit on or through the Tacx Service and you do so at your own risk.

**  
Does Tacx offer opt-out or opt-in services?**

Yes. If you choose to stop receiving emails from Tacx, please follow the unsubscribe instructions within each email communication or send an email to support@tacx.com. Tacx will process your opt-out and you will receive an e-mail confirming that you have opted-out and that Tacx have stopped using/collecting your personal data as well as deleted it, if the personal data is no longer required by law. In addition, the confirmation email will provide instructions and a service list on how to further avoid providing Tacx with personal data in connection with any Products or Services that you may attempt to use or where applicable, still be permitted to use after you have opted-out. Tacx will not provide or share any mailing lists or other information about you to another company or service for promotional purposes. Any service related emails (to confirm a purchase, etc.) generally do not offer an option to unsubscribe as they are necessary to provide the service you requested.

**  
The rights of users**

If you need to correct, amend or delete submitted information that is inaccurate please contact Tacx at support@tacx.com. We will respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe, and in any event in less than 30 days. In addition, you may correct, amend or delete submitted information that is inaccurate by visiting “Edit Profile” on the Site or in the App.

Users have the right to withdraw their consent for the processing of personal data or the further processing of personal data by Tacx at any time. A withdrawal should be sent to Tacx at support@tacx.com. We will respond to your request in a reasonable timeframe, and in any event in less than 30 days.

In addition to the information contained in this Privacy Policy, you may be provided with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of your personal data upon request.

Users have the right at any time, to know whether their personal data has been stored and can consult Tacx to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. You may also ask us to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. You may withdraw your consent for the processing of personal data or the further processing of personal data by us at any time. Requests should be sent to Tacx at the contact information set out below. Users also have the right to lodge a complaint against Tacx with a supervisory authority.

In addition to the information contained in this Privacy Policy, you may be provided with additional and contextual information concerning the Products or Services or the collection and processing of your personal data upon request.

Users have the right to request to obtain and reuse their personal data for their own purposes across different services. Requests should be sent to Tacx at the contact information set out below.

**  
Privacy Policy changes**

If Tacx makes changes to any terms or conditions of this Privacy Policy, these changes will be posted on the Site in a timely manner. If Tacx decides to change this Privacy Policy, it will post those changes on this Privacy Policy and other places Tacx deems appropriate, which may include the Site, for a period of time Tacx deems appropriate, so that you are aware of what information Tacx collects, how Tacx uses it, and under what circumstances, if any, Tacx discloses it. We expect most such changes to be minor. Any non-material changes will take effect immediately upon posting of an updated Privacy Policy. However, there may be cases where changes to the Privacy Policy may be more significant. In such cases, We will first provide a more prominent notice. In case of a business transaction in which a portion or all of Tacx’s business is acquired, Tacx will notify you as described above in this paragraph. We will in any case not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit and informed consent.

Your continued use of our Products and Services after the effective date of the Privacy Policy means that you accept the revised Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the revised Privacy Policy, please refrain from using our Products or Services and contact us to close any account you may have created.

All prior versions of this Privacy Policy will be kept in an archive for your review upon request. More details concerning the collection or processing of personal data may be requested from Tacx at any time. Please see the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy.

**  
Contact information**

Tacx is responsible for this Privacy Policy.  
DATA CONTROLLER AND OWNER: Tacx B.V.,

By writing to us: Rijksstraatweg 52, 2241 Wassenaar, The Netherlands  
By email: privacy@tacx.com

Thank you for taking the time to read this Privacy Policy. Updated on **May 24, 2018**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of the Tacx Service, or your dealings with Tacx, please contact us at privacy@tacx.com

**  
Third parties**

The Tacx Service allows for direct interaction with external social networks or other external platform that are outside our control. The interaction and information obtained by the Tacx Service are always subject to the user’s privacy settings for each social network. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by other websites or other services. Information collected by third parties, which may include such aspects as location data or contact details, is governed by their privacy practices. You should exercise caution, and review the privacy statements applicable to the third-party websites and services you use. The following third parties may be used by the Tacx Service. We have tried to include an overview that is as complete as possible on all third parties, however, we cannot guarantee the truthfulness and completeness of this overview.

Users can sign in to the Cloud using Google, Facebook or a dedicated Tacx Account. Both Google and Facebook accounts are connected via OAuth2 (OAuth2 is an authorization framework that enables applications to obtain limited access to user accounts) web flows of Google and Facebook. Tacx accounts are handled completely by the Tacx Account backend. Users can also connect their Strava account to their Cloud account (this is part of the Software), the connection is also made via an OAuth2 web flow.

_Google Analytics_ _  
_ Google analytics gathers anonymous user data. In particular, it gathers the following data and provides it (anonymously and aggregated) to Tacx:

  * Numbers of users per age group;
  * Numbers of male users;
  * Numbers of female users;
  * Number of users per country;
  * Number of users per device;
  * Number of users per device operating system version:
  * Number of users per users interest group;
  * Number of active users;
  * Time users spend daily;
  * Whether or not users have made a purchase.

**_Firebase_** **  
** Firebase is used to collect data on errors in Android and iPhone Apps. Firebase and Fabric’s crash analytics track the failures in the Apps. Such error messages always contain a UUID, which is a 128-bit number used to identify information in computer systems, email and full name. Theoretically, error messages may contain more user information that the user entered into the App or gave access to when signing in with Facebook, Google, or by linking Strava.

_OAuth2 Account Connections  
_For each Google, Facebook, and Strava connection, the user has to confirm if he or she wants to share the data that the Software requests with the Software. The user can deny these requests, effectively disabling the connection. When making the connection the Software sends a scope to the OAuth2 provider in question which contains all the information it requests. The scope is as follows:

  * Facebook: email and public profile.
  * Google: email and profile.
  * Strava: write, full reading and writing rights to Strava account of the user.

_Mandrill_ _  
_ Mandrill is used to send emails to specific users. Mandrill contains templates defined by Tacx for several types of email. These are currently two types of email: TCX Export and Password Reset. These templates require the first name of the user and for sending, obviously, the email of the user is required. These data are provided by the Software or account backends. Further data required by these templates is generated by either the account backend or the Software backend. The actual content as it is sent to the user is stored in Mandrill for later reference. In the future, new types of email may require other use of data, logically this data will be provided by the account backend or the Software backend from their storage systems. For sending emails to single users, Tacx uses Mandrill. Some user data is synchronized with Tacx’s MailChimp account for use in the Tacx newsletter.

_MailChimp_  
MailChimp is used for sending newsletters to users, the Software synchronizes with Tacx’ MailChimp account. The Software backend synchronizes, from its data store, the following data with MailChimp: first name, last name, email address, language.

**Extensive overview of data that is collected**

The following systems may be used by the Software and App for storing user data. We have tried to include an overview that is as complete as possible on all data that is collected and through what settings or Software, however, we cannot guarantee the truthfulness and completeness of this overview.

Various user data is stored in the Tacx Cloud (which is part of the Software). Some of this data is sensitive data. All Tacx applications communicate with, and store their data through, two backend systems:

  * The Cloud backend stores user profile information and training data; and
  * The Account backend is used to authenticate users through email/password combinations and handles the web flow such as the Tacx.com website and TTX applications.

Both these systems store their persistent data in the Google Cloud data store. The Google Cloud data store stores data in the form of entities, which may have one or more indexed fields.

The Cloud data store contains all user profile data, activity, workout and social data.

_Account data store_ ** _  
_** Account data store is storage of Tacx Account credentials and tokens. It contains data used for user authentication based on email and password, and the OAuth2 flow directed towards the Software (for client apps that enter want to get a token from the Software).

_App_ _Info_ ** _  
_** App Info is information that is used over the App. It contains the name and version of this App, the name and version of the OS (operating system) adopted by this App and the name of the device this App is running on.

_Authorization Code_ ** _  
_** Authorization Code is the code generated when client applications request an authorization code according to the OAuth2 standard.

_Client_ ** _  
_** Client is data for authenticating and authorizing client applications. It contains the following data: (1) Client’s ID, regardless of its validity and; (2) Client’s encrypted secret and prefixes of valid redirect URI (uniform resource identifier) for the OAuth2 web flow.

_Cloud data store_ _  
_ Cloud data store is storage of all user profile and training information. It has a search index that duplicates some information.

_Cloud File Storage_ ** _  
_** Cloud File Storage is storage of user profile images. Files in the Cloud File Storage are stored in Protobuf, PNG, or Jpeg format. The PNG and Jpeg files concern profile images uploaded by the user. The following data may be stored in Protobuf files: (1) distances and heights measured in meters; (2) durations measured in seconds; (3) heart rates and cadence measured in Hertz; (4) power measured in Watt; (5) energy measured in Joule and; (6) speed measured in meters per second.

_Code_ _Identifier_ _Mapping  
_Code Identifier Mapping is used to map the code sent when a password reset request is made to the account for password reset.

_Course_ ** _  
_** Course is data about a course. It contains the following data: (1) course name; (2) course description; (3) course creation date, including where this course starts and ends measured in meters or seconds from the start of the training; (4) the target functional threshold power of this course; (5) the starting and maximum altitude, height climbed in meters, total distance uphill and downhill and cotacol points of this course, regardless of whether it is a full course; (6) thumbnail png image data and App Info and; (7) maximum, minimum and average segment value, depending on the type of course, value of power, heart rate or slope.

_Data_ _Track_ _ _  
__ Data Track tracks information about a certain part of the training, which is delimited by time or distance. It contains the following data: (1) starting and ending offset in time or distance, depending on the training type and; (2) zero or one of Gears Data Track, Location Data Track, Road Surface Data Track, or Training Goal Data Track.

Email Settings  
Email Settings is used to track whether or not the user will receive emails from the Software and which emails to receive. A link is included in each email message that allows the user direct access to its settings without having to log in. The code included in that link is stored in Email Settings Code, which contains the following data for identification: (1) email; (2) expiration data and; (3) user UUID (universally unique identifier).

_Email_ _User_ _Id_ _Mapping  
_Email User Id Mapping maps an email address to a user account.

_File_ _Info  
_File Info tracks files stored in the Cloud File Storage and their metadata, the UUID of the user who uploaded it in particular. File Info may contain data about the file stored in correspondence with fields from Cloud File Storage.

GearsDataTrack **  
** Gears Data Track tracks information on the number of teeth of the chain ring used and the number of teeth of the sprocket used.

GpsData **  
** Gps Data is a list of Gps Points.

GpsPoint **  
** Gps Point contains the following data: (1) the point’s position relative to the start of training and optional value interpreted based on the type of training, latitude, longitude and altitude and; (2) formerly used fields which include current video frame and timestamp.

LocationDataTrack **  
** Location Data Track tracks information on a location visited during the training and the name and type (one of none, climb, or place) of this location.

Payment Notification **  
** Payment Notification is used to manage payment through Adyen. Payment Notification tracks notifications sent by Adyen to the Cloud about payments.

Payment Transaction **  
** Payment Transaction relates a user to a subscription. It contains the following data: (1) amount; (2) creation date; (3) currency; (4) an end date if the transaction was completed in case of payment; (5) a reason for failure in case of failure; (6) the date of the last payment notification; (7) the UUID of the last payment notification; (8) the payment method; (9) the payment preference and; (10) the Adyen payment URI (uniform resource identifier) and its status.

Persistent Token **  
** Persistent Token stores OAuth2 tokens mapped to user accounts.

Power Mode Change **  
** Power Mode Change is a change of the power mode. It contains data about the time of the change, the distance from the start of the training and the newly set power mode.

Relation Subject **  
** Relation Subject is used to track relations between entities and the number of such relationships in the Tacx Service. It may track the following relations: (1) a user favoring a workout; (2) a user favoring an activity; (3) a user following another user and; (4) a user being followed by another user.

Road Surface Data Track **  
** Road Surface Data Track tracks information on the surface of the road encountered during the training. The data contained include its intensity and the type of surface (asphalt, concrete plates, cattle grate, hard or soft cobbles, stones, dirt, gravel, ice, or wooden boards).

Score ** _  
_** Score contains a required Score Info and an optional Score Data.

ScoreBicycleInfo **  
** Score Bicycle Info is information about the bike with which a score was recorded. It contains the following data: (1) the type of bicycle (racing bike, mountain bike, or triathlon bike); (2) its mass; (3) its air resistance coefficient and; (4) its projected frontal surface.

ScoreData **  
** Score Data contains lists of pauses, Power Mode Changes and Score Samples.

ScoreDeviceInfo **  
** Score Device Info is about the device with which a score was recorded. It contains the following data: (1) the serial of the device; (2) its firmware version; (3) its protocol type (one of the unknown, bushido, vortex, genius, satori, fec compatible trainer, neo, flow, heart rate sensor, power sensor, black track, cadence sensor, cursor control, virtual power blue booster, or virtual power blue matic, flux, magnum, virtual power booster, or virtual power blue twist) and; (4) its device type (one of the unknown, speed, power, cadence, heart rate, resistance, or remote control).

ScoreHeartrateSettings **  
** Score Heartrate Settings is settings for heart rate while recording the score. It contains the following data: (1) maximum and minimum heart rate; (2) heart rate threshold; (3) lower and higher limit for the display lines and; (4) heart rate zones Score Info.

ScoreInfo **  
** Score Info is information about the recorded score. It contains the following data: (1) the creation date of the recorded score; (2) legacy minimum and maximum heart rates in bpm as set during the user while recording the score; (3) starting power mode, distance travelled, duration, if a custom power was enabled, if the power mode was changed while recording the score; (4) heart rate Score Statistics; (5) power Score Statistics; (6) relative power in Watt/kg; (7) total energy output; (8) maximum and minimum heart rate limit as set by the user while recording the score; (9) average and maximum power mode if there are details about power; (10) cadence, or heart rate available for this score; (11) the user’s mass and functional threshold power; (12) AppInfo; (13) the user’s heart rate settings; (14) bicycle info; (15) device info; (16) the type of score (one of cycling, running, or unknown) and; (17) the raw distance travelled if virtual speed was used.

Score Sample **  
** Score Sample is a sample of the recorded score. It contains the following data: (1) the speed, power, distance and moment the sample was recorded; (2) cadence; (3) heart beat in beats per minute and; (4) power returned from the brake, energy output, heartbeat, raw speed and raw distance.

Segment ** _  
_** Segment is a segment of training. It contains the following data: (1) position where the segment starts in meters from the start of the training, and value which is interpreted based on the training it belongs to and; (2) fields that are no longer actively used which include latitude, longitude, altitude, video frame and video time stamp.

Segment Data **  
** Segment Data is a list of Segments.

Stats ** _  
_** Stats is statistics of a user over a period of time, regardless of the length of time. It tracks the following data: (1) average heart rate; (2) average power; (3) calories; (4) creator UUID; (5) distance; (6) heart rate map; (7) heart rate time; (8) number of activities; (9) power map; (10) power time; (11) time and; (12) user UUID.

Subscription **  
** Subscription of a user is tracked, which contains the following data: (1) cancel date if canceled; (2) which subscription this is a continuation of; (3) the type of continuation; (3) creation date; (4) end date; (5) reasons for failure if any; (6) the start date of the original subscription; (7) the payment method; (8) the plan and; (9) the start date.

Training ** _  
_** Training contains a required Training Info and an optional Training Data.

Training Data **  
** Training Data is data about training. It contains the following data: (1) zero or one of Gps Data, Segment Data or Video Data and; (2) a list of Data Tracks.

Training Goal Data Track **  
** Training Goal Data Track tracks the value and type (one of none, speed, power, cadence) of a training goal.

Training Info **  
** Training Info contains the following information about a training: (1) the creation date of the training; (2) its name; (3) its description; (4) its type (on of catalyst, Gps, or video); (5) type of its Segments (one of the following: slope over distance or over time, power over distance or over time, percentage of the user’s functional threshold power over distance or over time, power over distance or over time, percentage of the user’s functional threshold power over distance or over time, percentage of the user’s maximum heart rate over distance or over time); (6) its tags, either running or cycling; (7) its png thumbnail and app info and; (8) its test type, either none or cp20.

User ** _  
_** User consists of three fields, namely inactive fields which are once filled in but no longer used, fields for possible future use and fields that are currently in use. For each of these fields, the data collected are categorized as follows:

For a number of inactive fields which are once filled in but no longer used, it contains the following data: (1) air resistance coefficient, bike type and bike weight, and frontal surface area which are replaced by Bike Profile and; (2) URI (uniform resource identifier) of the previous images.

For a number of fields for possible future use, it contains the following data: (1) address, city, country, postal code and state for billing and delivery purpose and; (2) nickname, phone and website for miscellaneous purpose.

For a number of fields that are currently in use, it contains the following information or data: (1) dates: registration, last modification of profile, possible deregistration; (2) linked accounts: ids for Google, Facebook, Tacx Account, Strava, as well as a Strava token. The ids remain instead of the Strava token; (3) personal information: biography, data of birth, email, first name, heart rate threshold, heart rate zones, heights, last name, location, maximum heart zones, height last name, location, maximum heart rate, measurement units for display (metric or imperial), weight, resting heart rate, gender, threshold power, profile image url and subscription type; (4) setting: whether or not the user receives emails for downloading his score files after a training, whether or not the export scores to a linked Strava Account, and profile visibility to other users and; (5) fields imported by TTS: country, creation time, extra player, ID, signature and software language.

UserCredentials **  
** User Credentials contains the user’s email, first name, and encrypted password.

VideoData **  
** Video Data contains the following information or data: (1) a list of Video Points; (2) the name of the video; (3) the product ID of this video; (4) the type of this video, either normal or ergo and; (5) the frame rate of this video (if applicable).

VideoPoint **  
** Video Point contains the following data: (1) position where the video begins from start of the training; (2) its value which is interpreted based on the type of training; (3) its latitude, longitude and altitude and; (4) current video frame and the timestamp of that frame.

Workout ** _  
_** Workout contains the following data: (1) number of activities; (2) subscriptions allowing this workout; (3) average segment value; (4) category; (5) climbing distance and height; (6) cotacol points; (7) country; (8) creation date; (9) UUID of creator; (10) descriptions for different languages; (11) difficulty and distance; (12) end of the workout in meters from the beginning of the training regardless of whether this is a full course; (13) image url; (14) type of the indicator; (15) maximum segment value; (16) minimum altitude; (17) minimum segment value; (18) motion type (running or cycling); (19) name in different languages; (20) point of interests; (21) publishing date (if any); (22) type of segment; (23) start of the workout in meters from the beginning of the training; (24) tags; (25) references to training file; (26) type of training; (27) UUID and; (28) video qualities.

Looking for the privacy policy before May 25th 2018? Please find them [here](https://tacx.com/privacy-policy-old/).

Last updated May 24th, 2018.

This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish.Accept [Read More](https://tacx.com/it/cookie-policy/)

Please note: due to the upcoming holidays all orders placed between May 29th and June 2nd will be processed after June 3rd and be shipped after this date as soon as possible. Our apologies for any inconvenience this may cause. Dismiss
